<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>urn:uuid:f9201c82-4e76-37cc-bbeb-73b44900f7f0</id>
  <title>Meta — Pallets Project</title>
  <updated>2023-02-12T19:47:14.159702+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/"/>
  <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/categories/meta/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>urn:uuid:702ce8fe-4fa2-3372-98c7-7d625108b121</id>
    <title>Hello Pallets Users</title>
    <updated>2016-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Armin Ronacher</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the first of April 2010, I released a joke microframework called denied
which made fun of the fact that all microframeworks at the time decided to
forgo with dependencies and bundle up everything they need in a single Python
file.  What I did was embed all of Jinja2 and Werkzeug in a base64 encoded
zip file within the framework's only Python file.  The response to it was
interesting in a few ways because on the one hand quite a few people did not
really understand that it was an April fools joke to begin with and on the
other, there was a discussion where there were no microframeworks that actually
did use dependencies and encouraged it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month later there was a new project by the name of "Flask" which actually
gave this concept a real shot.  It launched with the tagline "a microframework
for Python based on Werkzeug, Jinja 2 and good intentions" and six years later
it's the most starred Python framework on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's interesting about Flask is that its success just happened.  There are
no conferences about it, no society or foundation and still today much of it
heavily depends on me directly.  I'm not even sure why it became this
successful but I attribute a lot of it to the fact that it's easy to get
started and the full footprint of the framework is small enough that it becomes
easy enough to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what's changing now?  Today we launch the Pallets Projects.  What is it?
Primarily it's a GitHub organization which will be the home of Flask and all
the associated projects.  It will be a new home for those libraries and the
first step to give the community more impact on the development of Flask and
all libraries.  In addition there will be a new release of Flask very soon
after a thorough check that we do not break anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people behind the Pallets Projects are &lt;a href="/people/mitsuhiko/"&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="/people/untitaker"&gt;Markus Unterwaditzer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="/people/davidism/"&gt;David Lord&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="https://github.com/ThiefMaster"&gt;Adrian Mönnich&lt;/a&gt; with the organization
being open for newcomers to help and drive the projects forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will spend the next few weeks adding as much organizational information on
the project's website to ensure that what often currently only exists in my
head is brought down to text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm amazed how many people use and love Flask and my libraries and I hope that
this organization will be a good step towards making this scale past me.  It's
humbling how big all of this became.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/hello/" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>urn:uuid:e2546e79-67a9-3130-8ecd-2ba5cf46d946</id>
    <title>Donate to Support Pallets</title>
    <updated>2018-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>David Lord</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pallets is excited to announce that we have joined the Python Software
Foundation's Fiscal Sponsorship program. As a non-profit organization,
the PSF will accept donations on behalf of Pallets into a dedicated
account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donations enable more attention from maintainers, which translates into
more time devoted to fixing bugs, developing features, and making
quicker releases. &lt;a href="https://psfmember.org/civicrm/contribute/transact?reset=1&amp;amp;id=20"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to donate today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pallets organization develops and supports Flask, Jinja, Werkzeug,
Click, and other Python libraries. These libraries power applications of
all sizes around the world, and are downloaded millions of times each
month. Despite their popularity, the projects are primarily maintained
by only a few developers. The goal of Pallets is to grow the community
around these projects to create a sustainable group of contributors and
users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your donation will help:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow maintainers to devote more of their time to the projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize outstanding contributors in the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow maintainers and community members to attend conferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquire infrastructure and developer tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponsor local meetup events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like the work we do, you may donate as an
individual. If your employer uses Flask or any of the Pallets projects,
reach out to them to donate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flask and the Pallets team depends on you, the community. We thank you
for all the contributions you've already made, and look forward to
growing the community even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://psfmember.org/civicrm/contribute/transact?reset=1&amp;amp;id=20"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to donate today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/donate/" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>urn:uuid:ce6c8bfc-6cb8-3219-baa0-d129e028e892</id>
    <title>PyCon and Adding Maintainers to Click</title>
    <updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>David Lord</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In May I attended PyCon US 2018 in Cleveland, Ohio. It's a great opportunity to meet people interested in the Pallets projects and Python web applications. It can be a little intimidating, but also a lot of fun. The biggest difficulty is that there are &lt;em&gt;too many&lt;/em&gt; things to do, and I always wish everyone could have a few more days together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the main conference, while talks are happening, anyone can organize "open spaces," impromptu meetings for any topic. I organized a Pallets open space, and we had a huge turnout. I was kind of unprepared for the size, so we started with people asking me questions, and then split up into tables for new users, Flask, Click, and Jinja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/blog/pycon-2018-click/open-space-board.jpg" alt="Open space announcement"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For up to four days after the talks, developers get together for sprints, working together to contribute to Python open source projects. Experienced developers help new ones learn how to contribute, and everyone gets to learn about new projects and meet the developers behind them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/blog/pycon-2018-click/open-space.jpg" alt="Pallets open space"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the open space, I had mentioned that no one had really been maintaining Click for the past year. It turns out a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of people use Click. They came motivated from the open space to contribute during the sprint. Some were new to contributing, but they all had one thing in common: they knew how Click was being used more than I did! So I took a chance and gave them all write permissions to the repository. Click started at ~250 open issues and 68 pull requests. After 2 days, it was at 140 issues and 22 pull requests. Wow! With that success, I'm officially welcoming all these new maintainers to the Pallets Click team. While Click stole the show, we had great contributions to Werkzeug, Flask, and Jinja as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/blog/pycon-2018-click/sprint-dinner.jpg" alt="Dinner with Pallets sprinters"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get involved, a great way is to &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/watching-and-unwatching-repositories/"&gt;watch our repositories on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. You'll get notifications for each issue, so you can see what's happening and start contributing. You can help by triaging issues, improving tests and documentation, and fixing bugs. If your company uses a Pallets project like Flask, Click, or Jinja, consider pointing them to our &lt;a href="https://www.palletsprojects.com/donate"&gt;PSF donation page&lt;/a&gt;. Donations will help get maintainers to more events so we can do more sprints like this one. Thank you to everyone at PyCon and in the community for making Pallets a success!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/pycon-2018-click/" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>urn:uuid:f50d4ddc-5f5b-3ca0-a7ea-bfa01f601ed0</id>
    <title>Take the Pallets / Flask Community Survey</title>
    <updated>2019-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>David Lord</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my goals as a Pallets maintainer is to build the community around our projects. The Pallets projects (Flask, Jinja, Click, etc.) are downloaded millions of times each month, but it's hard to get a clear picture of what our users do and want with downloads stats only. We'd like to learn about you and your projects. Knowing more about our community will help us decide what to focus on to grow the Pallets projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/forms/CtZrOgWUa8gy1FNz2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to take our Community Survey.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please share the link with friends, coworkers, and the internet!  We're looking forward to seeing everyone's responses! You can follow &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PalletsTeam"&gt;https://twitter.com/PalletsTeam&lt;/a&gt; or this blog to get updates about Pallets, including the survey results.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/community-survey-2019/" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>urn:uuid:d45fe7ad-b9f8-389f-a18f-837dc367c287</id>
    <title>Ending Python 2 Support</title>
    <updated>2019-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>David Lord</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Upstream support for Python 2.7 is ending on &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0373/"&gt;January 1, 2020&lt;/a&gt;.
Pallets is joining the &lt;a href="https://python3statement.org/"&gt;community of open source projects&lt;/a&gt;
ending support for Python 2 at that time. Our statement and support plan
are based on &lt;a href="https://docs.pytest.org/en/5.3.2/py27-py34-deprecation.html"&gt;PyTest's announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be dropping support for Python 2.7 as well as Python 3.5 and
below, as their support windows have ended or will end around the same
time. Future releases of each Pallets project will only support Python
versions still supported upstream, which can be found in the
&lt;a href="https://devguide.python.org/#status-of-python-branches"&gt;Python Developer's Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last version branch of each core project to support Python 2.7
and Python 3.5 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flask 1.1.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Werkzeug 1.0.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click 7.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jinja 2.11.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ItsDangerous 1.1.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MarkupSafe 1.1.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each project will receive a major version bump to indicate support
for only 3.6+:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flask 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Werkzeug 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click 8.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jinja 3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ItsDangerous 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MarkupSafe 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;code&gt;python_requires&lt;/code&gt; package metadata, Python 2.7 and
3.5 users with a modern pip version will install the last supported
version automatically even if later versions are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team will no longer backport patches for unsupported versions, but
the branches will continue to exist. The team will be happy to
accept patches contributed by the community for any severe security and
usability issues until mid-2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made this decision based on multiple factors. Foremost is ease of
community contribution and maintainer availability. As time goes on,
fewer contributors have used or are familiar with the differences
between Python 2 and 3. Contributors and maintainers must keep track of
an ever growing list of obscure compatibility issues and workarounds,
and cannot use many modern features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last two years, we've talked to many developers and teams at
conferences and meetups and heard overwhelming support for the move to
Python 3. This is backed up by data collected from our community in a
survey we ran during January 2019, with 92% of respondents already using
or actively upgrading to Python 3. The &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/research/python-developers-survey-2018/#python-3-adoption"&gt;PSF developer survey&lt;/a&gt; and
PyPI statistics report similar majorities and show adoption continuing
to increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone in the community for your support, and to everyone
who has made this transition a reality. We look forward to continuing
to develop the Pallets projects with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/ending-python2-support/" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>urn:uuid:cadae415-3ba4-3b50-9cca-e4c8a5f6b410</id>
    <title>Introducing AAASE junior board</title>
    <updated>2022-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"/>
    <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/pallets-community-org/" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>urn:uuid:f45fb2d2-0fca-327c-b7bd-73f1266bc117</id>
    <title>AAASE Junior Board Mental health initiative!</title>
    <updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A blog about AAASE junior board mental health initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://aaasejuniorboard.com/blog/quart-pallets/" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
