<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sem on AAASE</title>
    <link>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sem on AAASE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AAASE Summer Academy</title>
      <link>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/summ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/summ/</guid>
      <description>The Junior board hosted a panel on youth activism and advocacy at the AAASE 2022 Summer Academy in Princeton University to share our motivations and experiences. We hope to encourage more young people to join us! Our parent organization, the Asian American Academy of Science and Engineering, hosts an annual Summer Academy to engage high school students in interactive lectures, leadership &amp;amp; entrepreneurship workshop, lab and campus tours, project design presentation &amp;amp; mentoring provided by experts from academia and industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission Statement</title>
      <link>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/mission/</guid>
      <description>The AAASE Junior Board is a nonprofit organization that ​
Celebrates our diverse Asian American cultural identities Encourages open dialogues on current affairs Facilitates accessible exchange of knowledge and promotes social advocacy </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the Junior Seminar Project</title>
      <link>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/sem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/sem/</guid>
      <description>Our goal is to Provide a platform for young Asian Americans to Engage in important discussions of our times Encourage action and initiatives Build a community to learn, grow, and have fun together! Each semester, we collect topic proposals that fall under a common theme. We then ask project leads to share the proposal with the public and invite participants to form focus groups. The project lead is expected to organize focus group discussions, and each group will decide their timeline and deliverables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTube channel</title>
      <link>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/yt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityadlele.github.io/aaase/sem/yt/</guid>
      <description>Follow us on YouTube ​ </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
